C&C Generals: Zero Hour — Archipelago Mod
Archipelago is a multiworld randomizer framework.
Items found in one game can unlock progress in another.
This mod integrates Zero Hour into that network.
Units, buildings, and upgrades become randomized items.
Enemy unit clusters are spawned at map locations.
Defeating them sends "checks" back to the network.
This is an engine-level mod — 4,400 lines of C++
built on a modernized source port. Not a map hack.
Everything you're about to see is running
in real-time in the game engine.
You start with almost nothing.
Basic infantry, dozers, and supply buildings.
Everything else is locked until the
Archipelago network delivers it. Every seed is different.
Unlocks are cross-faction — one item unlocks
the equivalent for USA, China, and GLA.
Items arrive from the Archipelago network.
New unit categories appear in the build menu.
29 unlock groups cover the full roster — infantry,
vehicles, tanks, aircraft, upgrades, and buildings.
Enemy unit clusters are spawned at fixed map positions.
These are the Archipelago checks.
Each cluster is a coordinated group.
They guard a position and fight as a team.
Hover over a unit to see its check ID.
Destroying the cluster completes the check.
Attack one unit and the entire cluster retaliates.
They coordinate as a group.
Each unit has a two-tier leash — a soft defend radius
and a hard max chase limit.
Beyond the chase limit, units always retreat —
faster movement, healing, and damage reduction.
After retreating, a 5-second cooldown prevents
them from immediately re-engaging.
With all items received, the full roster unlocks —
over 300 unit and building templates.
Time to test the limits of the
spawned unit protection system.
Spawned clusters are protected by a 91-rule damage matrix.
Superweapons deal zero damage.
They're immune to EMP, hijack,
hacker disable, and sniper vehicle kills.
4x health, 140% weapon range, and built-in stealth detection.
These are not easy targets.
To complete a check, defeat the cluster
with conventional firepower — no shortcuts.
Each completed check sends an item into the
Archipelago network — for you or another player.
Work in progress. The Archipelago network connection
is next — this demo uses local test fixtures.
Built on the open-source SuperHackers engine port.
Follow the project for updates.